<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Global Digital Assets Corporation]]></title><description><![CDATA[GDAC]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/news</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 04:33:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence Versus Covid-19: The Digital Defense]]></title><description><![CDATA[Disruptive technologies are being called to action by Covid-19. Without the standards of the technology we are already blessed with, it...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/artificial-intelligence-versus-covid-19-the-digital-defense</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ead726e50988a00c7938d50</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 13:22:52 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d24_f93fd894964e4c3cb30724ab55043e1b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disruptive technologies are being called to action by Covid-19. Without the standards of the technology we are already blessed with, it is likely that we would have all been far worse off, and thanks to our latest technological breakthroughs, we have plenty of power to fight back.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d24_f93fd894964e4c3cb30724ab55043e1b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2>Mapping and Monitoring</h2><p>Artificial intelligence (AI) is one technology that is playing a significant role in tackling Covid-19. At present one of our best strategies is the monitoring of the spread, contact tracing, and maintaining good social distancing standards. AI has the capacity to do all of the above, all the while allowing for remote data analysis across many healthcare applications.</p>

<p>Earlier in April, the Israeli Ministry of Health leveraged an AI-based triage platform from a domestic company called Diagnostic Robotics. Reportedly, the company adjusted its platform to create analytics, risk assessment, and prediction models specifically for Covid-19.</p>

<p>This scheme was rolled out nationwide, monitoring coronavirus-related symptoms daily. The platform analyzes patient symptoms, underlying health issues, and then the AI builds a risk profile as well as offering guidance for what to do next with a patient.</p>

<p>This is, however, a team effort; medical staff get patients/clients to fill out a questionnaire via text message, and by doing so, the remote screening process is able to create a continuous, large-scale assessment of the pandemic in real-time.</p>

<p>The platform also delivers “red flag” information to health authorities, which identifies coronavirus hotspots, creating opportunities for medical services to be as efficient as they can be as they’ll be able to identify and prioritize regions in need.</p>
<h2>Antibody Testing</h2><p>In Vancouver, Canada, AbCellera Biologics became the first North American company to receive a Covid-19 blood sample – within days the firm had identified approximately 500 antibodies that have the potential to treat Covid19 and is the largest number of antibodies discovered ever to be reported. In those days, the team screened over five million immune cells, and two days later these antibody-secreting cells were sequenced, leading to the massive uncovering of 500 antibody candidates.</p>

<p>The process moved so quickly in fact, that AbCellera sought out a drug development company so that tests and treatments could be produced as soon as possible, with a contract signed within 10 days.</p>

<p>AbCellera is a leading group within the Pandemic Prevention Platform Program, which was initially launched by the United States Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) as a means to combat unknown pathogens within 60 days.</p>

<p>AbCellera uses cutting-edge technologies like AI, genomics, big data and single-cell analysis to accomplish their aims, and if anything, the rapid success of their screening process goes to show not only how effective these technologies are, but how fortunate the world at large is for having such innovations in place.</p>

<p>In times of crisis and when there is a common enemy, the efforts of humanity are something to behold. This is especially true on the technological fringes where nascent and complex technologies that are yet to be understood in full, are being sent to the frontline of one of our greatest challenges yet.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dubai Blockchain: Elrond &#38; GDA Corporation Exploring Fast Payments &#38; Smart Contract Frameworks]]></title><description><![CDATA[Elrond Network, the European startup building the internet-scale blockchain which brings 1.000x improvements over existing similar...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/dubai-blockchain-elrond-gda-corporation-exploring-fast-payments-smart-contract-frameworks</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5eac19c48b595a00175444d2</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 12:46:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_c9aa4911c8134d6b9df0325ee38093a4~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_c9aa4911c8134d6b9df0325ee38093a4~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><a href="https://elrond.com/" target="_top" rel="noopener">Elrond</a> Network, the European startup building the internet-scale blockchain which brings 1.000x improvements over existing similar implementations, and <a href="https://www.gdacorporation.com/" target="_top" rel="noopener">Global Digital Assets Corporation (GDAC)</a>, the professional services company engaging with high growth economies and regions to enable innovation, have today started an agreement for research & development.</p>

<p>The Dubai Blockchain Strategy aims to make Dubai the first city fully powered by blockchain. It tackles three strategic pillars of Government Efficiency, Industry Creation and International Leadership. The implementation of the use cases for each of the pillars will be made after a rigorous selection of technologies and implementation partners.</p>
<blockquote>“<em>The blockchain space knows Elrond for its significant performance and scalability, but in addition to this our enterprise partners also recognize the implications of other noteworthy contributions in the areas of smart accounts & contracts. Together, these components make the Elrond blockchain uniquely equipped for real use-cases that go far beyond what we have seen so far.</em>” said <strong>Beniamin Mincu, Elrond CEO.</strong></blockquote>
<p>Elrond Ltd. and GDA Corporation are exploring the implementation of fast payments & clearance networks, as well as the definition and implementation of smart contract frameworks. The partnership is working off of Elrond’s scalable infrastructure and multiple innovations around smart contracts & smart accounts to define a fitting working model for Dubai and deploy it on the Elrond blockchain.</p>
<blockquote>“<em>Our focus on fostering efficiency through digitization is made so much easier when innovative companies bring clear solutions to some of our roadblocks. We are excited to collaborate with Elrond Network and hack at modern problems in exciting new ways</em>”, says <strong>Ashton Hettiarachi, Partner at GDAC.</strong></blockquote>

<p><strong>**Article published by Elrond through; </strong><a href="https://medium.com/elrondnetwork/dubai-blockchain-elrond-gda-corporation-exploring-fast-payments-smart-contract-frameworks-599952c45e35" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://medium.com/elrondnetwork/dubai-blockchain-elrond-gda-corporation-exploring-fast-payments-smart-contract-frameworks-599952c45e35</a> </p>
,About Elrond<p>Elrond is a new blockchain architecture, designed from scratch to bring a 1000-fold cumulative improvement in throughput and execution speed. To achieve this, Elrond introduces two key innovations: a novel Adaptive State Sharding mechanism, and a Secure Proof of Stake (PoS) algorithm, enabling linear scalability with a fast, efficient, and secure consensus mechanism. Thus, Elrond can process upwards of 10,000 transactions per second (TPS), with 5-second latency, and negligible cost, attempting to become the backbone of a permissionless, borderless, globally accessible internet economy.</p>

<p>Contact email: <a href="mailto:contact@elrond.com" target="_top" rel="noopener">contact@elrond.com</a></p>

<p>For more information, visit: <a href="http://www.elrond.com/" target="_top" rel="noopener">www.elrond.com</a></p>,]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Internet of Things Versus Covid-19]]></title><description><![CDATA[Though an exhaustive and often morbid subject, the global response to Covid-19 has been quite a heart-warming spectacle to witness. The...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/the-internet-of-things-versus-covid-19</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ea97526d1203b001839e2de</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 12:47:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_42f6b8286f304bd9b354dfcb26eb5cfb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Though an exhaustive and often morbid subject, the global response to Covid-19 has been quite a heart-warming spectacle to witness. The world is collectively tackling a pandemic, leveraging the latest and greatest technologies to beat this pandemic. Without these new tools we may have been facing darker days, but we are equipped better than ever to take it on.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_42f6b8286f304bd9b354dfcb26eb5cfb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2>Tracking, Tracing, Monitoring</h2><p>Though it is almost impossible to be perfectly prudent in the anticipation of an invisible enemy, it is certainly spurring on rapid and radical developments in technology across the board. Though some technologies are beginning to shine a little brighter than others, and of all the technologies out there, the Internet of Things (IoT) may be one of the most effective on the frontlines.</p>

<p>IoT technologies have been applied in healthcare/hospital settings for quite some time; multiple devices/sensors all gathering and sharing critical pieces of data in real-time, allowing for faster responses to changes in patients conditions or even with wearable technologies such as Fitbit or the Apple Watch that can monitor your health, and report it if need be.</p>

<p>Ultrasounds, thermometers, electrocardiograms, and any other device that can be connected or used to monitor the health of an individual can be traced and tracked, which can even result in the automation of healthcare such as automated deliveries of pharmaceutical supplies, or smart-dispenser devices that notify users when they need to take their medication.</p>
<h2>Coming for Covid-19</h2><p>At the highest end of IoT technology, devices can collect patient data without human touch, which in the instance of our current pandemic is a potential life-saver on both ends of care services.</p>

<p>Reducing exposure to the virus is, at present, our best defense; VivaLNK, a Californian company was recently leveraged by the Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center (SPHCC), alongside Cassia Network, to bring in Bluetooth IoT products and solutions to the frontline of Covid-19 patient care.</p>

<p>VivaLNK’s sensors monitor body temperature in real-time, and this data is sent through Cassia’s database and IoT Access Controller, a management tool that allows staff to get a holistic view of patient vitals; reportedly, these solutions are being leveraged in several other hospitals in China and may have been significantly conducive to the reduction of transmission.</p>

<p>IoT also has a place in the monitoring of staff and equipment locations. Real-time location systems (RTLS) are commonplace in IoT networks; when paired with wearable devices, hospitals and care centres can monitor and track the number of patients, doctors, or people in any given location. This is incredibly potent as hospital administrators can monitor who has, for example, been in a high-risk quarantine area, and who they may have come in contact with before and after.</p>

<p>These are just small examples of IoT in times of crisis, but they true beacons of hope. IoT sensor data can interface with almost any industry and sector it needs to, and in our current pandemic, there has never been a better time to stretch the capacity of these technologies.</p>

<p>Technology is gunning for Covid-19, and IoT is just one weapon in humanities arsenal, watch this space, there’s plenty more to come.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Industry 4.0: China’s Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) Begins Testing]]></title><description><![CDATA[China is finalizing its plans to roll out a central bank digital currency (CBDC), with trials presently underway. The nation has been...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/industry-4-0-china-s-central-bank-digital-currency-cbdc-begins-testing</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ea70de6b88999008509b32c</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:59:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_3b85ade56b30461d857e21ab55ea5743~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China is finalizing its plans to roll out a central bank digital currency (CBDC), with trials presently underway. The nation has been exemplary in its continued efforts to adopt fourth industrial revolution (4IR) technologies apart from cryptocurrencies, which is still a work in progress, making the introduction of the Digital Yuan all that more fascinating in the world of Industry 4.0.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_3b85ade56b30461d857e21ab55ea5743~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2>Experimental, Novel, New</h2><p>Physical money has been slowly dwindling in usage, in fact cashless/digital payments have unstoppably become the dominant method of payment, which was to be expected with the proliferation of mobile banking apps, contactless debit cards, and so on. Though for a government to officially issue its national currency in digital form is an extremely new concept that appears to make total sense. If we are paying digitally, why isn’t our money digital?</p>

<p>The Bank of England was one of the earliest organizations to flirt with the notion of CBDCs, and even now Sweden is conducting tests of its own CBDC, the e-krona, which will be based on blockchain technology. However, the aim of the e-krona is not to replace cash, but to complement it.</p>

<p>China, despite its ban on cryptocurrencies, which was somewhat reversed or is presently reversing, is moving full steam ahead with the testing of its CBDC project, which in China is officially dubbed as a “digital currency electronic payment” (DCEP).</p>

<p>Ironically, the governing body behind the creation of the CBDC, the Digital Currency Research Institute, was set up on 2017, the same year that the People’s Bank of China (PBoC) had ordered all commercial and financial entities to cease handling cryptocurrencies, as well as banning initial coin offerings (ICOs) at the time.</p>

<p>In this short time, the institute put together around 1,000 staff members to create the new digital fiat currency. Reportedly, the currency has two uses, commercial and everyday uses, as well as internal bank transfers. It is hoped that the Digital Yuan, which will be backed 1:1 by China’s national currency, the Renminbi, will boost the speed of the nation's legacy banking systems.</p>

<p>Regarding the technology backing the DCEP, it is somewhat clear that blockchain will not be the foundation for it, rather, a number of technologies. Though this is ambiguous, it is worth noting that China leads the world in blockchain-related patent applications, and has introduced blockchain into its online government services.</p>

<p>China’s foray into digital transformation is unprecedented as they are leading the world in terms of smart city development, blockchain adoption, IoT, DeFi investment, and so on.</p>

<p>According to Jay Hao, the CEO of OKEx, one of the world’s biggest Bitcoin/cryptocurrency exchanges, the DCEP being a 100% state-backed digital currency makes it a far more tangible digital currency, unlike decentralized currencies like Bitcoin, or stablecoins like Tether (USDT), which have troubles when it comes to payment processing or even adopting the technology. With the DCEP, it’s legal tender, and merchants cannot refuse DCEP payments.</p>

<p>In an interview with Hackernoon, Hao also noted that DCEP opens up the doors for financial inclusion, further increases anti-money laundering and tax evasion crackdowns, decreases terrorist funding and improves financial service quality for those in “underdeveloped and remote areas.”</p>
<h2>Testing Grounds</h2><p>Naturally, the CBDC needs to be tested out in the field, and so far, China has put together a roster of participants and locations including several state-owned banks who will also be partaking in the experiment as well as telecommunications companies, this is likely to establish solid network infrastructure.</p>

<p>Furthermore, a list of commercial participants, including western companies like McDonald’s and Subway are part of the test. This is wise, as they are enterprises that deal in huge levels of transactions and if anything, reveal whether or not the infrastructure of the CBDC is ready for such adoption.</p>

<p>The CBDC is to be tested in four major cities across China, namely Shenzhen, Suzhou, Chengdu, and Xiongan New Area. Reportedly, the cities that they are being tested in were carefully selected as they reside on the outskirts of Beijing as part of the “smart city brain project.”</p>

<p>Xiongan New Area will most certainly be one to watch, as this is a city with highly advanced infrastructure being developed in it. 4IR technologies such as 5G networks, IoT, blockchain, and big data facilities will be the foundation on which this super city will operate, primed for the introduction of a CBDC.</p>
<h2>Getting Ahead</h2><p>In the coming weeks, we’ll have a better picture of just how well the CBDC has performed, especially amid the COVID-19 crisis, as China slowly begins to upstart its economy again, slowly returning people back to work.</p>

<p>Though China’s CBDC has been a great point of contention for economists around the world, as they believe the introduction of the Digital Yuan challenges the dominance of the U.S. dollar.</p>

<p>Whilst the project has been in the works for some years, it received a boost of confidence in 2019 from China’s leader, Xi Jinping, who spoke of embracing digital finance and blockchain in order to gain an “edge over the other major countries.”</p>

<p>As seen with cryptocurrencies, and even in the case of Venezuela’s state-backed cryptocurrency, it seems that the development of CBDCs with all the functions of a traditional currency is a mammoth task. Creating the currency alone is not enough, it needs to be proven to work just as well as the traditional economic ecosystem, and if not, perform far better, and that is how it will be accepted by its people.</p>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Curious Case of Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Adoption in China]]></title><description><![CDATA[Blockchain technologies and cryptocurrencies have long been a baffling mixture of contention and positivity in China. Over the course of...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/the-curious-case-of-blockchain-and-cryptocurrency-adoption-in-china</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ea38eb43eb6f30017bc479f</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 01:26:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_d8fc38ddd973479687334712d86790ce~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Blockchain technologies and cryptocurrencies have long been a baffling mixture of contention and positivity in China. Over the course of almost 8 years, the nation has gone from banning cryptocurrency activities altogether, to building the largest Bitcoin mining regions in the world. With the nation soon to introduce a central bank digital currency (CBDC) and a world-leading number of blockchain patent applications, China is indeed the most fascinating nations to watch.</strong></p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_d8fc38ddd973479687334712d86790ce~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<h2>The Curious Case of Crypto in China</h2><p>In the curious case of cryptocurrency, China is perhaps the biggest outlier for regulatory and legislation flip-flopping. Though perhaps the crypto-skeptical pro-blockchain nation may be prudently testing the waters of this new tech in a fashion unlike any other. Crypto bans, a national central bank digital currency (CBDC), blockchain-based government portals, and huge investment into DeFi make China one of the most curious sagas in the brief history of blockchain.</p>

<p>In 2017, cryptocurrencies were in vogue, the markets were red hot with innovations and scams with thanks to the largely unregulated and new novel fundraising method used by crypto-related companies known as initial coin offerings (ICOs). At this point in time, the value of Bitcoin reached its highest point, breaking past $20,000, and with it, many other cryptocurrencies rose to fame.</p>

<p>Since then, many have died off, many have survived, and very few were deemed legal by China’s authorities. In 2017 China banned ICOs entirely, resulting in a nervous quake for the cryptocurrency market. But the rally against cryptocurrencies began in March 2013, when the People’s Bank of China (PBoC) declared that cryptocurrencies were no longer recognized by the state as legal tender or a viable retail option. Even cryptocurrency mining farms were hit, with over a hundred companies being forced to shutter their doors. It seemed as though cryptocurrency and blockchain technology was doomed in one of the world’s largest economies.</p>

<p>Prior to this, in the Winter of 2013, the PBoC officially prohibited banks and payment companies from engaging with them altogether. Later in December of that year, the government officially deemed bitcoin a “virtual commodity”, giving it some regulatory classification, and this is essentially where the story of endless policy amendments began.</p>
<p>Throughout 2018-19, the narrative in china was “blockchain not crypto”, despite continued investment into crypto-infrastructure building companies. In June of 2019, the PBoC released a statement, declaring that it would ban all access to domestic and foreign cryptocurrency exchanges”.</p>

<p>However, cryptocurrency trading has resumed in China with many switching to foreign exchanges such as those based in Hong Kong, Japan, and South Korea, regardless of the ban. Though as you may have already come to realize, matters aren't quite as they seemed.</p>
<h2>The Switch</h2><p>In July of 2019, this all changed. In a landmark ruling that came soon after PBoC’s ‘ban’, transformed sentiments almost overnight. Chinese courts finalized that Bitcoin is a “virtual property”, noting it had value, could be disposed and had scarcity – the hallmarks of inherent utility, which are vital attributes to any property, especially digital currencies.</p>

<p>In November of 2019, things began to change quite radically. In an edition of China’s Industrial Structure Adjustment Catalog, cryptocurrency mining will no longer be subject to a state crackdown. Since then, China has become the biggest manufacturer. Furthermore, China is home to the biggest cryptocurrency mining industry in the world, further obscuring its stance on the technology. In 2019, Bitcoin mining raked in $5.4 billion and according to data, China mines more Bitcoin than anywhere in the world, and also is home to some of the biggest producers of mining hardware manufacturers and mining pools like BitMain and Canaan Creative.</p>
<h2>Patent Pending</h2><p>As per data from LedgerInsights.com (2019), out of the top ten companies in the world with blockchain patent applications, Chinese firms hold seven of those positions. All top three companies are in China, Alibaba/Alipay presently hold 1505 patents, Tencent with 724, Ping An Group holding 561 and four others with a total of 975 between them, bringing China’s total patents up to 3,765 – which is likely to have increased since then.</p>

<p>It must be noted that blockchain patents aren’t all that straightforward, and some reports may include patent applications relating to cryptography, which can include blockchain or other security-related applications.</p>

<p>As Ethereum co-founder/creator Vitalik Buterin Tweeted: <em>“If you're bragging about how many "blockchain patents" your country/company/organization has, you don't understand blockchains.”</em></p>
<h2>Blockchain Adoption</h2><p>In a recently published whitepaper from the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC), the paper noted that over 70 Chinese financial services companies, which included all state-managed banking institutions and China’s largest technology firms, are all using blockchain-enabled financial applications in one form or another.</p>

<p>One example is the ICBC’s international trade settlement platform for China and Europe; built on blockchain, the platform can verify and sync shipping/supplier data which is shared by firms, banks, government entities, etc.</p>

<p>Alibaba also recently partnered with the government of a Chinese province to stamp out food fraud and boost consumer trust. The project brings together both blockchain and an Internet of Things (IoT) tracking system for total transparency.</p>

<p>The above examples are becoming quite typical stories in the adoption of blockchain technologies, but there may perhaps be a cherry on the cake, especially considering China’s odd relationship with the technology overall.</p>

<p>Reportedly, an alliance of Chinese government groups, banks, and major tech companies are banding together to launch what is titled the “Blockchain-based Service Network” (BSN). It is intended to act as an operating system, where users can quite simply access blockchain programs or build their own, something akin a sandbox. Though most importantly, it is a historical moment as this will be the first major blockchain network owned and maintained by a central government.</p>

<p>Most excitingly of all, there are rumors that the network will integrate two of the most popular blockchain networks for decentralized finance (DeFi) protocols and decentralized applications (dApps), Ethereum, and EOS, respectively.</p>

<p>What this could mean for the development of blockchain/cryptocurrency/DeFi in China is almost impossible to tell, though as inconsistent they have been, there is no doubt in their mind that one, if not all of these technologies will have a future there. Though what form and shape that will take is anyone's guess.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Industry 4.0: A Global Evolution]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are entering into a brand new industrial era, with this one being our fourth. New emerging technologies are either improving or...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/industry-4-a-global-evolution</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e8f86da8c331c0017a602a3</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:50:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_06bbf2af85d04f19a10af4345410e216~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>We are entering into a brand new industrial era, with this one being our fourth. New emerging technologies are either improving or replacing old ones yet again. In this time we will see not just robots and machines replacing jobs previously held by humans, but also new novel automation processes that could reach as far as law. </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Industry 4.0 in Vogue</strong></h2><p>The fourth industrial revolution (4IR), also known as Industry 4.0, refers to the myriad of new technologies that are disrupting every major industry and sector in the world, and in some cases, industries of their own. It’s an amalgamation of physical, digital and biological worlds, fusing cutting edge technologies like robotics, artificial intelligence (AI), the Internet of Things (IoT), genetic engineering, blockchain, 3D printing and quantum computing amongst many others. </p>

<p>According to experts around the world, these technologies have already begun to, or will be, underpinning many of the existing technologies and industries we have today, if not make them obsolete entirely. These technologies are proliferating into almost every sector and industry on the planet, and are creating a symbiosis that has never been witnessed or experienced before.</p>

<p>Though it’s not just industries and institutions that are being swept up in the 4IR maelstrom; these technologies have bled into our everyday lives. While they may not be completely mainstream-ready like the World Wide Web or even virtual reality, they are most certainly on their way.</p>
<h2><strong>Big Tech, Big Changes</strong></h2><p>IoT, big data, cloud computing and 5G networks are already having gigantic impacts on the lives we live. These technologies encompass perhaps the ‘engine, oil and fuel’ of the fourth industrial revolution, especially given their widespread adoption.</p>

<p>Speaking with Arunkumar Krishnakumar, an investor, prolific entity in the world of BigTech, and Author of the book “Quantum Computing and Blockchain in Business”, we took a look at the some of the issues facing the evolution of 4IR technologies.</p>

<p>Krishnakumar begins by highlighting what he thinks is the most crucial factor in all of this, data, he writes:</p>
<blockquote>“Industry 4.0 relies on data ubiquity. Technologies such as AI, IoT, Blockchain, and Quantum Computing rely on data. Data, in turn, relies on mobile internet. The introduction of 5G will be the much-needed oil in the system. “</blockquote>
<p>Being an advocate of technological-inclusion for the world, he sees the growth in internet users in Asia, which is dominated by both India and China, as great news for Industry 4.0. He believes that once this increase in internet access amongst rural populations, or “the last mile” as he describes it, has connected more of the world, then that is when 4IR technologies will be at their most impactful.</p>

<p>Across the board, industries like manufacturing, automotive vehicles, logistics, finance and farming are not only in the midst of 4IR transformation, but they are also pioneering. Blockchain technologies appear to be finding themselves favourable amongst financial institutions and industries that are reliant on supply chain and data analytics; IoT technologies, as well as AI technologies, are becoming mainstays in the agriculture sector as well as being built into smart cars and vehicle production lines.</p>

<p>One of the latest to join the all-star team of disruptors is 5G, a technology purported to beef up the performance of the aforementioned technologies, especially in sectors with automation technology implemented.</p>
<h2><strong>Technological Displacement</strong></h2><p>Though the typical knee-jerk response is the fear of people losing their livelihoods, which does indeed unfortunately occur; it is not always doom and gloom. With every industrial revolution, new and exciting enterprises and careers are also created, though even this can prove troublesome.</p>

<p>In a 2019 discussion report from the World Economic Forum (WEF), it is noted that the technological displacement of workers has indeed been something of a historical fact, though that doesn’t paint the full picture. According to the WEF, the problem is that there will actually be an abundance of new work available, and fears that there won’t be enough skilled workers in these fields. </p>

<p>KPMG released a 2020 report titled “The 2020 Fourth Industrial Revolution Benchmark”, detailing present sentiments and projects from around the world. Perhaps one of the largest takeaways from the report suggests that overall, almost half of all companies surveyed didn’t feel prepared for technological change, or have stated that establishing the correct staff/skill capability is their biggest challenge. Though 4 in 10 companies felt that they have the staff ready to take on the new tech.</p>

<p>IOA Africa is one such establishment that in its recent report, comprehensively broke down the requirements for 4IR to blossom in the nation. Notably, the report concludes that there are numerous reasons for the lack of 4IR preparation, highlighting the lack of technical infrastructure, a lack of relevant education curriculum, and educational stakeholders failing to collaborate effectively on the matter.</p>

<p>That said, institutions, governments and educators are well aware of the fact, with some of the most well established academic institutions in the world rolling out University degrees, courses and internships to foster the next generation of 4IR workers. For example, both Oxford University (UK), Stanford University (USA) are offering blockchain and AI courses respectively. </p>

<p>Amongst those are many others who, in anticipation of the 4IR future, are readying to provide industries with at least enough workers to support the 4IR industry.</p>
<h2><strong>Mainstream Ambitions</strong></h2><p>Arunkumar notes that of course, these technologies also have some significant challenges ahead before they land in the mainstream. Although they’re influencing our daily and future lives, these technologies are still quite young, regardless of how fast they seem to grow.</p>

<p>Arunkumar elaborates:</p>
<blockquote>“Many of these technologies have challenges before they can go mainstream too. For instance, AI needs to overcome data quality and data ethics challenges. Blockchain needs to get governance and controls to avoid retail misuse. Quantum computing has its own challenges with stability (of qubits), we are at least a decade away from mainstream adoption. The IoT infrastructure we have is vulnerable to new-age cyber threats.”</blockquote>
<p>To paint the full picture, he offers the example of implementing mobile payment infrastructure on to roadside flower shops in India; before doing so, he is clear that the owner is aware of the cyber risks involved and if possible, are mitigated. Otherwise, according to Arunkumar: “...data ubiquity can become a threat.”

He concludes:</p>
<blockquote>“In essence, for Industry 4.0 to impact the layman, we will need to overcome technological limitations and create the required controls to protect consumers.”</blockquote><h2><strong>Right Revolution, Right Time?</strong></h2><p>Although the line has been blurred with regard to when the transition from our present industrial state to 4IR began, it is again important to note that it is already happening and is in an extremely nascent state.</p>

<p>Though, with the world pressing the ‘digitization’ button more than ever, it is anticipated that these technologies will be dominant forces for decades to come, though it would be of little surprise that at some point, something else will come along to replace even these incredible achievements. </p>

<p>Perhaps in 2020, there has never been a better time to go full-steam ahead with 4IR technologies. Early-adoption may have it’s risks and even disappointments, but it also spurs on the rest of the competition out there to become more accessible, simplified, cheaper, efficient and future-proof. </p>

<p>With more and more companies, investors and institutions getting behind these efforts, the sooner that 4IR will be realised in all its glory, the sooner the world as we know will transform once again.</p>

<p>
</p>





]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[GDAC Appointment by Dubai Future Council on Blockchain for Dubai Future Foresight Initiative ]]></title><description><![CDATA[In January of 2020 the GDAC team was appointed by the Dubai Future Council on Blockchain (part of the Dubai Future Councils initiative...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/gdac-appointment-by-dubai-future-council-on-blockchain-for-dubai-future-foresight-initiative</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e97a39841ea660017ca4bc8</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_204fd6470c734f179fb23b4a8028e543~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_204fd6470c734f179fb23b4a8028e543~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>In January of 2020 the GDAC team was appointed by the Dubai Future Council on Blockchain (part of the Dubai Future Councils initiative launched by HH Sheik Hamdan Bin Mohammed Al Maktoum in March 2018) and Smart Dubai as the main partner to the Dubai government initiative on creating a comprehensive future foresight analysis on the future of emerging technologies (Like DLT’s) in Dubai’s most viable sectors.</p>

<p>Since the blockchain boom around 3 years ago, Dubai has been extremely active in the emerging technology space, from their Dubai Blockchain Strategy mandate for 2020, to their Dubai 2021 Paperless Strategy. This foresight initiative brings a strong focus on the future of the region and how Dubai can play a leading role in creating a preferred emerging tech driven future.  </p>

<p>Foresight is used to create both awareness about the external environment and also to enable strategists, industries, cities and nations to pre-emptively react to changes and disruptions. Foresight is not a prediction tool, but rather it is a process, which allows for the identification of discontinuities, pinpointing of technological trends, assessing of promising emerging technologies, and also navigation of future business opportunities. This process involves methods and techniques for gathering, assessing, and interpreting relevant information and supporting decision-making, - in order to help foster a preferred future through collaboration.</p>

<p>Additional objectives are to provide early warnings about potential threats, and support planning and shaping of the strategy. Foresight helps to validate these early warnings, evaluate the possible strategic impact, and provide recommendations, as well as build networks around certain issues or problems. </p>

<p>Conducting a foresight exercise on Dubai’s emerging technology innovation will help to cultivate a new generation of solutions, stress the possibility of different future states, and facilitate cooperation in growing the region’s productivity and economic growth through technological implementation and favourable policies. </p>

<p>The aim of the engagement is to work with government departments, local communities, leaders and SMEs, helping to foster conversations, bring to light new opportunities and position Dubai as a leader in the broader emerging technology global stage.</p>

<p>Since the teams appointment at the start of the year, they have engaged with multiple stakeholders in Dubai from both the public and private sectors in a number of key industries (Financial services, trade and logistics, real estate and construction, transportation and tourism) to perform a deep environmental scan (Political, economical, social etc.), identify gaps and opportunities and also gain a sound understanding of the fundamental bottlenecks and challenges within the ecosystem. </p>

<p>They have been looking at new futuristic use cases to be implemented and actioned in the Dubai private and public sectors and also how emerging technologies can be used to facilitate a more seamless citizen experience and information flow between and within the public and private sectors. The team was able to identify over 54 use cases, which have now be refined and prioritised to a leading 20. </p>

<p>These use cases will be presented to the Council to help define and outline the action plan as to how Dubai can help to position itself as a leader in the Blockchain and broader emerging technology space; with a focus on addressing more structural, fundamental opportunities. This includes rethinking blockchain-native infrastructures, governance models, ecosystems, business models and technology initiatives.</p>

<p>GDAC has also been engaging with a number of local and globally based industry leaders and experts to help bring new perspectives and iteration to their work and identify best practises for areas of future development focus. </p>

<p>Overall, this initiative is a great additional stepping stone for Dubai's emerging technology roadmap and GDAC is more than honoured to have been invited to take part. </p>


<p>

</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[DeFi, Ready for the World?  ]]></title><description><![CDATA[As with every nascent technology, Decentralized Finance (DeFi) is bound to encounter many teething problems. However, with the increasing...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/defi-ready-for-the-world</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e84f3b269bd6a0017f5af32</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 20:07:16 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_77f83cbcebdc45b4be2195adb599958d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>As with every nascent technology, Decentralized Finance (DeFi) is bound to encounter many teething problems. However, with the increasing adoption of cryptocurrency and blockchain technologies, is DeFi prepared to handle the demands of both emerging and troubled economies?</strong></p>
<h2><strong>Developing Growth</strong></h2><p>With global internet access slowly becoming a standard for more than half the world’s population, interacting with technologies that break away from societal norms, or even ones that aren’t offered, has never been easier. DeFi, a sector of the ever-growing blockchain industry, is looking as though it may be primed to establish a new status quo in the world of finance.   </p>

<p>Backed by stablecoins such as Tether (USDT) and other cryptocurrencies such as Ethereum (ETH), DeFi platforms are offering up versatile solutions, services, and tools to establish a robust and complete financial ecosystem.  </p>

<p>Bitcoin (BTC) is an example of DeFi at its most primitive, a digital asset with value that can be exchanged between individuals. Since the advent of Bitcoin, the roots of DeFi began to blossom, laying the foundations for what could become a true alternative to traditional finance. For economies lacking in infrastructure, this could be revolutionary.  </p>

<p>Speaking with Aly Madhavji, a managing partner of the Blockchain Founders Fund, he noted:   </p>
<blockquote>“Nigeria is a particularly interesting market given that they have the most searches for the term ‘Bitcoin’ in the world. Organizations such as <a href="https://www.coin4sales.com/" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>Coin4sales</u></a> in Nigeria allow you to pay for mobile credit or utility bills with Bitcoin while Binance is creating a locally denominated stablecoin.”  </blockquote>
<p>However, he notes that DeFi is still in its early phase. According to him, there is a high demand for cryptocurrency lending products though these tend to attract wealthier individuals, though he notes that these products aren’t suitable for “broader use” due to their high-risk nature. However, in the case of Venezuela’s hyperinflation crisis, Bitcoin became a saving grace against the devaluation of the nation's fiat. Though according to him, such solutions don’t quite work out for everyone and unfortunately, <em>“...don’t have the traction to replace high inflation national currencies...”. </em><em> </em></p>

<p>Though contrary to this, speaking from the benches of the Kyber Network, one of DeFi’s darling protocols, the firms head of ecosystem growth, Deniz Omer, agrees, noting that though DeFi is an important tool for wealth preservation, is may not be ready for the mainstream just yet. Citing his first-hand experience of Cyprus’s 2013 crash, he recalls having financial control being taken away from him, watching his finances decline in value and even the confiscation of bank deposits, Omer sees DeFi as a great equalizer.   </p>
<blockquote>“Blockchain and DeFi are the radical new technologies that can provide a wide range of financial services that take the balance of power away from central bankers, and distribute it trustlessly and transparently across a permissionless network.”  </blockquote><h2><strong>Early Days </strong></h2><p>Though it may not be prepared for the mainstream, it is evident that DeFi is going to be playing a role in our lives for many years to come, with both Madhavji and Omer anticipating a steady growth of adoption.  </p>

<p>There are still a couple of key problems, amongst many, that need addressing before a decentralized economy can thrive. For one, platforms and services in DeFi are inherently linked to volatile assets that aren’t exactly cheap to transact domestically, and secondly, the technology just isn’t quite ‘there’ yet.  </p>

<p>In developing markets where unbanked citizens can’t access financial services due to lack of ID’s or even banking solutions, even having an internet connection may fail to suffice.   </p>
<p>Madhavji writes:   </p>
<blockquote>“This poses the problem of completing KYC and AML requirements to be able to access on-ramps into any cryptocurrencies in the first place. Low fee, localized solutions for utilizing bank transfers to buy cryptocurrency and locally denominated stablecoins are critical pieces of the puzzle along with identity authentication.”  </blockquote>
<p>That said, there are platforms such as LocalBitcoins and Paxful where users without formal/government-issued identification can purchase cryptocurrencies directly from another person through a number of payment methods, including cash. Though access to such crypto-gateways isn’t widespread knowledge, which may change at some point soon.   </p>

<p>If accessing crypto isn’t a problem, then Omer certainly believes that DeFi has a lot of maturing to do in order for mainstream adoption to be achieved. For Omer, the digital ecosystem of DeFi is complicated and doesn’t quite function as it could. But Omer is optimistic, noting that the entire Ethereum network is soon to launch ETH 2.0.   </p>

<p>If the present Ethereum network has managed to achieve what it has done in its current state, then ETH 2.0 could be a silver bullet to the aforementioned problem areas. Looking ahead, Omer writes:   </p>
<blockquote>“... more mainstream adoption can be as close as half a decade away. There are also multiple competitors to Ethereum and this competition accelerates the growth in innovation even further and I believe brings mainstream adoption even closer.” </blockquote><h2><strong>Ahead of the Curve </strong></h2><p>With respect to the current economic climate amid the Covid-19 pandemic, DeFi solutions, at least as a hedge against a potential global recession, could be cause for the tech to be further adopted.  </p>

<p>As mentioned earlier, cryptocurrencies come in two flavours, volatile and stable. Those that retain their value i.e. stablecoins, are essential components to the DeFi ecosystem.   </p>

<p>In short, stablecoins are cryptocurrencies that have their value verifiably backed by a basket of fiat and/or assets, thus guaranteeing their worth. These cryptos are especially prevalent with USDT sitting in the top ten cryptocurrencies by market cap at all times, highlighting the breadth of utilization either as a tool within DeFi or simply a hedge against market volatility.  </p>
<p>In the case of a recession, one would assume that this would negatively impact the stability of such cryptos, in fact, Madhavji and Omer argue that this is not the case. Accordingly, the U.S. dollar would play a leading role in a global recession as nations and investors to respond in a manner where they require more dollars, which strengthens the dollar <em>“relative to other fiat-backed currencies”</em>, according to Madhavji.  </p>

<p>Though the future is impossible to see, there are many individuals and entities in the world who are tapping this nascent technology for the betterment of civilization. If the technology and minds behind DeFi continue to paddle upstream, especially throughout this year, we could see the financial landscape change forever.   </p>

<p>Whilst it may not be this year, or even next, DeFi’s big moment in the spotlight is seemingly overdue. With all the protocols and services available, the numerous updates and endless upgrades, it’s only a matter of time before DeFi is on the tip of the world's tongue, just as Bitcoin was in 2017 and has been ever since.  </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stablecoins are the Backbone of DeFi  ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stablecoins have become far more than just a hedge against market volatility; recent data displaying transactional dominance over the...]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/stablecoins-are-the-backbone-of-defi</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7e13fc594d480017c4e051</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 15:06:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d24_dfa64ba225784a1680295749ad896592~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stablecoins have become far more than just a hedge against market volatility; recent </strong><a href="https://twitter.com/RyanWatkins_/status/1222533131011534851" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,<strong>,<u>data</u></strong></a><strong> </strong><strong>displaying transactional dominance over the Ethereum economy suggests that they are beginning to form the very backbone of the digital economy. With more innovations on the horizon, Decentralized Finance (DeFi) and stablecoin-payment platforms are primed to establish a </strong><a href="https://www.etoro.com/blog/market-insights/what-role-will-stablecoins-play-in-crypto-mass-adoption/" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,<strong>,<u>new financial standard</u></strong></a><strong> </strong><strong>for the world. </strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d24_dfa64ba225784a1680295749ad896592~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2>Evolving Stability </h2>
<p>Tether (USDT) is the most recognizable stablecoin on the market, and despite numerous controversies, it still reigns supreme in the markets. Pegged 1:1 against the U.S. dollar, USDT has spent much of its life being the people’s choice stablecoin. Over time however, other market players sought to capitalize on this product, creating new models that support the value of their coin, or creating new ways in which they can be utilized outside of trading, and that’s where DeFi comes in. 

For example, MakerDAO is a firm on the frontlines of stablecoin promotion and innovation with their leading decentralized model that is analogous to mortgages or loans, bolstered by the DAI stablecoin. Here, users can leverage their Ether (ETH) to create a Collateralised Debt Position (CDP) and accrue DAI, which can then be sold for ETH and reinvested should the user choose to do so. They can also lend, send, and borrow through the MakerDAO Oasis platform.   

There are many other DeFi protocols such as dYdX and Compound that also offer similar interest-yielding products.   

Interestingly, DeFi appears to be the new hedge against market volatility, as reports indicate that DeFi protocols are being increasingly leveraged during market downturns. </p>
<h2><strong>Stablecoin Payments and Regulation Pains</strong></h2>
<p>South Korean stablecoin project, Terra, has witnessed nothing but <a href="https://twitter.com/d0h0k1/status/1209244843857235968?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1209244843857235968&#38;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2F2019%2F12%2F24%2Fkorean-stablecoin-cryptocurrency-used-at-major-stores-sees-massive-spike-in-volume%2F" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>staggering growth</u></a> over the course of December 2019.  </p>

<p>Reportedly amongst other successes, the project's payment platform landed a <a href="https://www.econotimes.com/Terra-cryptocurrency-trading-volume-rose-by-280-as-adoption-of-the-stablecoin-increases-1570952" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>significant</u></a> partnership with CU, the nation’s foremost retail chain which boasts more than 13,000 outlets, indicating both <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/audio/2019-11-07/blockchain-drives-mobile-payments-platform-chai-radio" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>public and institutional demand</u></a> for stablecoin payment systems, hopefully foreshadowing the direction of South Korea’s digital economy.  </p>
<p>The recent explosion of adoption could also be attributed to the news that Terra is expanding its blockchain payment network into <a href="https://e27.co/blockchain-payment-network-terra-expands-to-singapore-with-former-uber-exec-in-leadership-20191219/" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>Singapore</u></a>, capturing a far broader audience. </p>

<p>In the western world, similar strides are being made albeit in a cautiously staggered fashion. Facebook’s stablecoin project ‘Libra’ has had regulators <a href="https://www.financemagnates.com/cryptocurrency/news/will-facebooks-libra-launch-this-year-or-even-at-all/" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>biting back</u></a> against the concept as they are of the impression that it could undermine sovereign currencies, not to mention the potential ramifications of a privately owned and centralised global currency. Though somewhat extreme, this sentiment may have some footing due to the absolute global reach of Facebook, which isn’t to say that it wouldn’t be a benefit to the broader global community. </p>

<p>There is some progress being made in France, as recently the First Deputy Governor spoke openly on the <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/robertanzalone/2020/02/01/frances-deputy-governor-outlines-a-path-for-stablecoin-payment-systems/#647e953c527c" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>opportunities and risks</u></a> presented by stablecoins and their respective payment systems. </p>

<p>U.S. Fed Governor Lael Brainard also <a href="https://www.crowdfundinsider.com/2020/02/157289-fed-governor-lael-brainard-discusses-digitalization-of-payments-and-currency-says-fed-is-researching-cbdc/" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>spoke</u></a> on the matter, noting the influence that BigTech and FinTech startups are having on digital payments and the economy overall.  </p>

<p>Acknowledging the blossoming of peer-to-peer payment systems and <em>“new business models that bundle payments with other activities in novel ways.</em>”, she concludes that these disruptors offer great benefits to the consumers all the while promoting financial inclusion to domestic and global audiences. </p>
<h2><strong>What Next?</strong></h2>
<p>Stablecoins will likely have to prove their worth over and over again in order to edge toward mainstream adoption. Though to their benefit, a good stretch of the road ahead has already been paved by Bitcoin, Ethereum, and other major cryptos that have gone through years of scandals, technological overhauls, </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7b17b3_f1771364d67e43a48bf1698b9da9962d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>innovations, and regulatory hindrances, which should allow for a smoother journey toward their final destination. </p>

<p>Stablecoins aren’t immune to controversies or scrutiny, and if anything, they have far more to prove in order for governments and industries to take them seriously.  </p>

<p>Over the past few years, we have seen regulators shift toward positive sentiments for major cryptocurrencies, with a major example of this being the continued adoption of Ripple (XRP) into traditional financial systems and <a href="https://www.fxstreet.com/cryptocurrencies/news/ripples-xrp-is-in-the-verge-of-mass-adoption-eric-dadoun-202001300937" target="_top" rel="noopener noreferrer">,,<u>legacy banks</u></a>.  </p>

<p>Though with all the discussion, innovation and adoption already taking place, 2020 could finally be the year that stablecoins turn the tables completely, becoming the world’s go-to cryptos forevermore.   </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dubai To Transform by 2021: Smart Cities Envisaging Opportunities for Innovation
]]></title><description><![CDATA[The United Arab Emirates has formulated numerous policies and plans that are aimed at promoting its sustainable development goals.]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/dubai-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3681e6494d110017bdb010</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 13:49:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1b3711_0018a57b61e44f27b89b56806f956fdb~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_926,h_576,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Arab Emirates has formulated numerous policies and plans that are aimed at promoting its sustainable development goals. The country has been working to transform its cohesive society, competitive knowledge economy and sustainable infrastructure to transform into one of the most tech-centric countries in the world. To promote and make these goals come alive the authorities are shifting their focus from conventional techniques to smart futuristic solutions, powered by technologies like AI, IoT, Blockchain, Robotics, Big Data and Machine Learning. The inclusion and evolution of Smart Cities will form the basis on which Dubai will be built to sustain and empower its economy.</p>

<p>Dubai’s ambitious plan of developing a Smart City that covers more than 545 projects cutting across multiple segments strives to give opportunity to international tech startups and SMEs to explore the market opportunities and present their innovative solutions. The UAE government has set-up millennial goals that will revolve around using core technologies like AI, IoT, Blockchain, Big Data and Robotics</p>
<p>to create a smarter tomorrow by 2021.</p>
<p> </p><blockquote><strong><em>How Do They Propose To Achieve a Smart City by 2021?</em></strong></blockquote>
<p>Such an ambitious plan demands a proper approach for its fulfilment and the government has framed the roadmap that calls for a collaborative association of some top stalwarts in the technology domain to build a better connectivity plan. In this pursuit, they are using state-of-the-art technology for safety and security measurement. “Police without Policemen '' is one such ambitious project that addresses certain sustainable development goals in creating a safer neighbourhood. Here, ‘Smart Dog technology’ is used to include a Wi-Fi enabled 360 degree CCTV view that will link houses directly with the police stations via raw footage recording. This airborne surveillance program will minimise the dependability of patrolling by policemen and automate the protection of citizens.</p>

<p>This is just one of the many projects proposed and undertaken by the authorities, another being the Digital DEWA Project, which is the first project in the world that uses automated AI powered renewable energy to give an unhindered supply of solar power and energy storage to the region.</p>

<p><strong>Building a Competitive Economy Using High-End Technology Solutions.</strong></p>

<p>Dubai and other regions in the Emirates have been eager to welcome smart innovations engineered by emerging technology startups to enter their soil and bring transformative evolution for the betterment of the economy. The launch of the Dubai Blockchain Policy complements this millennium vision, with 100% of applicable transactions to be conducted on the Blockchain by 2020.</p>

<p>The Dubai Blockchain Policy will function via 4 stages, with the participation of more than 68 attendees that will include startups, banks, government & semi-government bodies to set- up a clear plan and outline the process of integration and execution of blockchain technology in the specific function of key departments in Dubai.</p>

<p>To include a notable mention of a blockchain technology use case in the Dubai automobile industry, the Dubai Vehicle Chain will manage and maintain all the vehicles registered with the Road and Transport Authority and automobile manufacturing units in Dubai. The total of these 545 projects will influence 1,100 essential government services in Dubai and result in the annual revenue generation to the tune of USD2.83 billion by 2021.</p>

<p>Traffic congestion, environmental pollution and lesser use of public transport have posed significant challenges towards attaining a clean environment and hassle-free travelling experience for citizens. As a result, some of the leading government agencies have proposed the use of smart technology integration to improve transportation. The Smart Parking Project is one such addition where IoT sensor technology will be used to automatically provide information to the vehicle owners of parking space availability and also allow for more streamlined payment of parking tickets.</p>

<p>Further, another pioneering project includes the Road and Transport Authorities Smart Traffic Management System that is set to increase <strong><em>“the smart system coverage of Dubai roads network from the present 11 per cent, to 60 per cent”</em></strong>, as reported by Mattar Al Tayer, the RTA Governor General and Chairman of the Board of Directors. The use of traffic monitoring and data systems will be powered by CCTVs and drones, vehicle detection devices, bluetooth devices and weather sensors.</p>

<p>Dubai will be launching its Smart City Expo in 2020 to specifically target and discuss the increasing demand for intervention of smart technology for better living standards and growth. Numerous startups in the technology domain will have significant opportunities to present their projects that will help in the development of a smarter Dubai.</p>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dubai Expo 2020 To Transform the Emirates As The Largest MarketPlace For Introducing Smart Tech]]></title><description><![CDATA[UAE’s giant strides in the technology domain to captivate sustainable development has attracted investors and businesses from different part]]></description><link>https://luckhetti.wixsite.com/mysite-4/post/dubai-smart-cities</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3681e6494d110017bdb00f</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 13:42:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1b3711_b8e51ed27c1d4fa199b2ec0c38f870c4~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_626,h_476,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>GDAC</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1b3711_b8e51ed27c1d4fa199b2ec0c38f870c4~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_626,h_476,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>UAE’s giant strides in the technology domain to captivate sustainable development has attracted investors and businesses from different parts of the world. Sensing this significant transformation as a great opportunity for many businesses cutting across wide domains, the 6 month World Expo 2020 event is to be held in Dubai, starting from October next year. The reputation of the UAE and Dubai as a technology hub has not been built overnight but rather by consistent efforts fuelled by bringing innovation and transformation to attract global businesses.</p>


<p><strong>Agenda of the World Expo 2020</strong></p><blockquote>The Dubai World Expo 2020 revolves around “Connecting Minds and Creating A Smart Future.” In order to carry forward this vision, the country has embraced cutting edge technology like Artificial Intelligence, Blockchain, IoT, Robotics and Machine Learning.</blockquote>
<p>The Expo will create multiple opportunities for these emerging technologies to solve key problems that require futuristic and advanced technological solutions. The UAE is inviting startups, technology companies to introduce their smart solutions that will help the region in attaining their sustainable development goals by revolutionising mobility and transportation in the economy. Thus, investors and companies from 190 nations will get an opportunity to focus on contributing to the economic growth, real-estate development, curbing environmental problems and simplifying public affairs through their technological products and services.</p>

<p>The World Expo will include over 190 countries and 200 participants from different nations, MNCs, businesses and educational institutes. The event will also witness more than 25 million visitors and over 30,000 volunteers.</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>The core aim of the Expo is to motivate and drive startups & SMEs to pitch their revolutionary ideas and roadmaps. The Expo sets to lead significant investments in innovation and architecture to build better endearing relationships with partner nations and create favourable business opportunities in the Middle East, especially the Emirates.</p>

<p>To keep up with such a pressing demand, Dubai has already started to invest significantly on infrastructure development by building new freeways, roadways and smart mobility solutions like air taxis and energy efficient cars. Many experts have anticipated that the event will increase the hotel occupancy by more than 70 million bookings and retail spending will increase around by USD 10 billion. Such a colossal investments will lead to the creation of more than 1,00,000 jobs in the span of 6 months, with a total spend of USD 8.7 billion being allocated for the project.</p>

<p>Dubai World Expo will not just be a huge gathering event, rather, it will transcend into a platform proposing key technologies, solutions and setting a futuristic roadmap to make Dubai and the Emirates one of the most advanced and futuristic countries in the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>